<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal growth | Musings from Rohail</title>
    <link>https://roumail.github.io/tag/personal-growth/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://roumail.github.io/tag/personal-growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>personal growth</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 18:24:31 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://roumail.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>personal growth</title>
      <link>https://roumail.github.io/tag/personal-growth/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unearthing Your True North</title>
      <link>https://roumail.github.io/personal-values-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 18:24:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roumail.github.io/personal-values-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!---
## The values I cherish and celebrate and remind myself to hold closer

1. Acceptance
2. Belonging
3. Creativity 
4. Curiosity 
5. Commitment
6. Simplicity 
7. Faith
8. Exploration
9. Humility
10. Expressiveness
11. Boldness
12. Perseverance

--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete me&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarantine Chronicles: How COVID-19 Helped me look inward</title>
      <link>https://roumail.github.io/personal-values-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 10:50:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roumail.github.io/personal-values-part-i/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#taking-the-plunge-and-buying-my-first-drum-set&#34;&gt;Taking the plunge and buying my first drum set&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-honeymoon-period&#34;&gt;The honeymoon period&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#choices-were-always-there-but-i-never-realised-the-implications-of-failing-to-choose&#34;&gt;Choices were always there, but I never realised the implications of failing to choose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#this-was-just-the-beginning&#34;&gt;This was just the beginning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across this quote from the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Essentialism-Greg-McKeown-audiobook/dp/B00IWYP5NI/ref=sr_1_1?crid=RZC41UQUFCF6&amp;amp;keywords=essentialism&amp;amp;qid=1698311094&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=essentialism%2Cstripbooks-intl-ship%2C150&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Essentialism&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;
by Greg McKeown earlier this year which very nicely encapsulates some of the
learnings and insights I&amp;rsquo;ve had over the period since COVID. The quote goes like
this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space to think, time to look and listen, permission to play, wisdom to sleep and the discipline to apply highly selective criteria to the choices we make&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;taking-the-plunge-and-buying-my-first-drum-set&#34;&gt;Taking the plunge and buying my first drum set&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the COVID period forced many of us to reconsider our routines and how
we process everyday events. One of the best things that came out of COVID for
me was to act on a childhood dream of mine - to learn to drum!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up in a house where we enjoyed listening to different types of Music. I
can relate to Music in a way that&amp;rsquo;s helped me go cope with the challenges life
throws at you. Listening to certain songs would transport you back in time to a
certain moment in your life so Music holds transcendental qualities for me. While
I certainly enjoyed air guitaring to some of my favourite guitar solos like Pink
Floyd&amp;rsquo;s comfortably numb, Drumming is something that had an inexplicable allure
for me. The raw energy and force that drumming is able to convey - the rhytmic
elements of Music was something I naturally inlined towards. And on March 30th
2020, my life was forever changed.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-yamaha-dtx-452&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Yamaha DTX 452&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /personal-values-part-i/AJLF3953_hua840194b759347812a16e5c141166fda_1531015_24aa08aee4d4eaeaf78c01715d500a70.webp 400w,
               /personal-values-part-i/AJLF3953_hua840194b759347812a16e5c141166fda_1531015_2e5762df0cd57295a4e39f6c9c144718.webp 760w,
               /personal-values-part-i/AJLF3953_hua840194b759347812a16e5c141166fda_1531015_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://roumail.github.io/personal-values-part-i/AJLF3953_hua840194b759347812a16e5c141166fda_1531015_24aa08aee4d4eaeaf78c01715d500a70.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;668&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Yamaha DTX 452
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-honeymoon-period&#34;&gt;The honeymoon period&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very glad I have an understanding wife and neighbours that didn&amp;rsquo;t complain
about the thumping sound and vibrations from my bass pedal. With drumming, I
suddenly had a whole new world open up to me. Youtube was my friend and I would
take advantage of platforms like &lt;a href=&#34;www.drumeo.com&#34;&gt;Drumeo&lt;/a&gt; to learn enough of
the basics to get started. I had always been an avid music fan but I&amp;rsquo;d never
learnt music theory and now suddenly, I realised that if I really wanted to make
the most of online material in my learning journey, I&amp;rsquo;d need to learn how to read
music. Thankfully, reading drum notation is rather straightforward compared to
other instruments (or so I think). Things were all well and good until I realised
one day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I make the time to practice and reach the drumming goals I&amp;rsquo;d set for myself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m quite a goal oriented person and so naturally I had set ambitious goals for
myself. These goals were different from the ones I&amp;rsquo;d been setting for most of
my life, which would often be related to studies or work. These were goals where
I didn&amp;rsquo;t care as much if I went off track. They were more like a north star and
had the ability to steer me back on course if I went too far astray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lo and behold, I saw that the best way for me to make the time to practice was
to start waking up at 5 am in the morning. Yes. 5 am. I had tried practice
at more reasonable times but it just wasn&amp;rsquo;t consistent. I had never thought
there&amp;rsquo;d by anything that would make me jump out of bed this way. And now I&amp;rsquo;d
found it. And I was jumping out of bed. During COVID. The drums helped me stay
sane - though likely at the expense of my understanding wife&amp;rsquo;s sanity 🤣.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was experimenting with different material, playing along to songs I loved and even started learning to play &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-handed_drumming&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;open handed&lt;/a&gt; where instead of crossing your hands so your right (for most people, dominant) hand is on the hihat keeping time and you use your left hand on the snare. By playing open handed, as a right handed drummer, I was using my left hand to keep time, which meant I was using it on average 4 times more than my right hand. This was incredibly awkward and frustrating in the beginning. However, I stuck to it and configured my kit to suit this style of playing too:&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-hi-hat-left-setup-incredibly-low-for-open-handed-playing&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Hi hat (left) setup incredibly low for open handed playing&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /personal-values-part-i/kit-setup_hu8b4f4db4d2a4b8d46a2052a4896f6c76_2077477_cedb6ddcfa6298de0ae9e97fd8cadd10.webp 400w,
               /personal-values-part-i/kit-setup_hu8b4f4db4d2a4b8d46a2052a4896f6c76_2077477_f010c97bdfe89e3ae187c88cffbac3b9.webp 760w,
               /personal-values-part-i/kit-setup_hu8b4f4db4d2a4b8d46a2052a4896f6c76_2077477_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://roumail.github.io/personal-values-part-i/kit-setup_hu8b4f4db4d2a4b8d46a2052a4896f6c76_2077477_cedb6ddcfa6298de0ae9e97fd8cadd10.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;570&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Hi hat (left) setup incredibly low for open handed playing
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical practice session eventually came to be an hour or more of playing
between 2-3 exercises, on a 15-20 minute break. Sound boring? I found it to be
rather meditative actually. This setup was a result of a lot of self-reflection
on what makes a good practice session. Benny Greb&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/56515701-effective-practicing-for-musicians&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Effective practicing for musicians&lt;/a&gt; had a lot of wisdom to share on
the topic and much like Essentialism, the message was the same: Choosing is not
losing. You need to make choices to go deeper and further on your topic of
interest. This is especially true for something like drumming where there is
more than an analytical understanding that you need to undertake to execute a
particular pattern on the drums. You need to literally drill that pattern down
into your body to the point where your muscle memory can take over and execute
the pattern instinctively at will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming to this realisation wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy. While it&amp;rsquo;s great having all this
information on our finger tips with platforms like youtube and social media but
these platforms are also a constant reminder of the different way&amp;rsquo;s that
you&amp;rsquo;re not &lt;code&gt;enough&lt;/code&gt; where you are right now. We are constantly bombarded with
what we don&amp;rsquo;t know, what&amp;rsquo;s cool and hip right now and 10 ways for you to
{{ insert a hyped up skill here }}.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;choices-were-always-there-but-i-never-realised-the-implications-of-failing-to-choose&#34;&gt;Choices were always there, but I never realised the implications of failing to choose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learnings I had from drumming could be easily transferred to other areas of
my life. I saw a number of parallels in my journey as a machine learning
practitioner. Scrolling through LinkedIn, is just a reminder of all the
technology frameworks you are yet to learn. That may not be everyone&amp;rsquo;s
experience but I bet a number of us feel that way. Feeling that way is normal
unless we become hyper aware of what exactly are the topics that we are
super-knowledgable and passionate about. And those topics have to necessarily
form a finite set, rather than one that changes depending which side of the
bed you went to sleep. The fear of missing out (FOMO) is what often prevents`
us from commiting to this finite set of topics that we dig our heels into.
Choosing one thing, necessarily means letting go of something else and who
wants that? Can&amp;rsquo;t we just have it all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back to my 5 am adventures, I was getting some exceptional results in
my drumming with the discipline of putting in the time consistently every day.
That was, until greed started to set in&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m quite big on productivity. I have a productivity system including a
number of tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.evernote.com&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; for taking notes,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.trello.com&#34;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; for big picture planning,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.sunsama.com&#34;&gt;Sunsama&lt;/a&gt; for a daily planner,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.todoist.com&#34;&gt;Todoist&lt;/a&gt; for capturing ideas and doing some tactical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prioritization,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google calendar and calendly for scheduling appointments,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.remarkable.com&#34;&gt;Remarkable&lt;/a&gt; for hand written digital notes that I can
send myself later for further processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the uninitiated, this would seem like a rather long list, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been
refining this system slowly over time and it feels very natural to me. Applying
Tiago Forte&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://fortelabs.com/blog/para/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PARA&lt;/a&gt; method allows me to
pretty much make sure nothing escapes my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    The productivity tools above may imply, to those in the know, that I&amp;rsquo;m following
some sort of &lt;a href=&#34;https://gettingthingsdone.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt; system.
However, I just kind of came up with this system on my own, following different
people on youtube who were probably taking inspiration from David Allen&amp;rsquo;s work.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waking up at 5 meant that I had roughly 4 hours before I started work and
that&amp;rsquo;s A LOT of time to get things done. Soon enough, I started to do more than
just drumming when I woke up at 5. I made a system where I tried to make sure
I &amp;ldquo;hit each area&amp;rdquo; a given number of times. You can think of it like going to
the gym and having a push/pull/legs like of setup. I was rotating through
different areas in my life to make sure &amp;ldquo;everything was in balance&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result you ask? I was no longer jumping out of bed anymore. I would wake up,
and look at the list of things I had planned to do for the time before 9 am.
There was likely also the fatigue from the long drawn COVID lockdowns coming
in, but I had basically taken the magic out of my mornings by overengineering
that time I had to myself. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, a number of good things came
out of this time, such as for example a scraper of immoweb that I wrote
around this time (see blog entry &lt;a href=&#34;https://roumail.github.io/a-scraper-that-scales-part-i/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before I started to wake up, only to hit the snooze
button and go back to bed once I saw the long todo list I had left for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew that I needed to reorient myself and get back to the basics. I had let
my greed, to get more done, get the best of me. I knew at this time that I
needed a value system that would help me decide what&amp;rsquo;s worth (to me) spending
time on and what&amp;rsquo;s better left on the backlog (or better yet, not even added to
the backlog to begin with!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-was-just-the-beginning&#34;&gt;This was just the beginning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be easy coming up a list of values to give me a
foundation. Making such decisions is hard! For example, if you had to choose
between knowledge and imagination, which value would you prioritize? What if
you had to choose between Integrity and Accountability? Not easy is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I explore how these insights helped me formulate my values in a following
&lt;a href=&#34;https://roumail.github.io/personal-values-part-ii/&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;. Stay posted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Soon, playing on the electronic kit wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough and I needed to rent out
a practice room
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-yamaha-dtx-452&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Yamaha DTX 452&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /personal-values-part-i/real-kit_hucdbd301978b6aa20cba4b1cc8f601d32_2518857_a8bbe05be4b6e7b591bf08a7361b890e.webp 400w,
               /personal-values-part-i/real-kit_hucdbd301978b6aa20cba4b1cc8f601d32_2518857_ab5ee5a0177452aa020f7c1db4511690.webp 760w,
               /personal-values-part-i/real-kit_hucdbd301978b6aa20cba4b1cc8f601d32_2518857_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://roumail.github.io/personal-values-part-i/real-kit_hucdbd301978b6aa20cba4b1cc8f601d32_2518857_a8bbe05be4b6e7b591bf08a7361b890e.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Yamaha DTX 452
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
