<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Musings from Rohail</title>
    <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://rohailtaimour.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Musings from Rohail</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://rohailtaimour.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Musings from Rohail</title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/event/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/event/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page elements&lt;/a&gt; such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unearthing Your True North</title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 18:24:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!---
## The values I cherish and celebrate and remind myself to hold closer

1. Acceptance
2. Belonging
3. Creativity 
4. Curiosity 
5. Commitment
6. Simplicity 
7. Faith
8. Exploration
9. Humility
10. Expressiveness
11. Boldness
12. Perseverance

--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete me&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarantine Chronicles: How COVID-19 Helped me look inward</title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 10:50:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-i/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#taking-the-plunge-and-buying-my-first-drum-set&#34;&gt;Taking the plunge and buying my first drum set&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-honeymoon-period&#34;&gt;The honeymoon period&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#choices-were-always-there-but-i-never-realised-the-implications-of-failing-to-choose&#34;&gt;Choices were always there, but I never realised the implications of failing to choose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#this-was-just-the-beginning&#34;&gt;This was just the beginning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across this quote from the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Essentialism-Greg-McKeown-audiobook/dp/B00IWYP5NI/ref=sr_1_1?crid=RZC41UQUFCF6&amp;amp;keywords=essentialism&amp;amp;qid=1698311094&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=essentialism%2Cstripbooks-intl-ship%2C150&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Essentialism&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;
by Greg McKeown earlier this year which very nicely encapsulates some of the
learnings and insights I&amp;rsquo;ve had over the period since COVID. The quote goes like
this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space to think, time to look and listen, permission to play, wisdom to sleep and the discipline to apply highly selective criteria to the choices we make&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;taking-the-plunge-and-buying-my-first-drum-set&#34;&gt;Taking the plunge and buying my first drum set&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the COVID period forced many of us to reconsider our routines and how
we process everyday events. One of the best things that came out of COVID for
me was to act on a childhood dream of mine - to learn to drum!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up in a house where we enjoyed listening to different types of Music. I
can relate to Music in a way that&amp;rsquo;s helped me go cope with the challenges life
throws at you. Listening to certain songs would transport you back in time to a
certain moment in your life so Music holds transcendental qualities for me. While
I certainly enjoyed air guitaring to some of my favourite guitar solos like Pink
Floyd&amp;rsquo;s comfortably numb, Drumming is something that had an inexplicable allure
for me. The raw energy and force that drumming is able to convey - the rhytmic
elements of Music was something I naturally inlined towards. And on March 30th
2020, my life was forever changed.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-yamaha-dtx-452&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Yamaha DTX 452&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /personal-values-part-i/AJLF3953_hua840194b759347812a16e5c141166fda_1531015_24aa08aee4d4eaeaf78c01715d500a70.webp 400w,
               /personal-values-part-i/AJLF3953_hua840194b759347812a16e5c141166fda_1531015_2e5762df0cd57295a4e39f6c9c144718.webp 760w,
               /personal-values-part-i/AJLF3953_hua840194b759347812a16e5c141166fda_1531015_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-i/AJLF3953_hua840194b759347812a16e5c141166fda_1531015_24aa08aee4d4eaeaf78c01715d500a70.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;668&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Yamaha DTX 452
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-honeymoon-period&#34;&gt;The honeymoon period&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very glad I have an understanding wife and neighbours that didn&amp;rsquo;t complain
about the thumping sound and vibrations from my bass pedal. With drumming, I
suddenly had a whole new world open up to me. Youtube was my friend and I would
take advantage of platforms like &lt;a href=&#34;www.drumeo.com&#34;&gt;Drumeo&lt;/a&gt; to learn enough of
the basics to get started. I had always been an avid music fan but I&amp;rsquo;d never
learnt music theory and now suddenly, I realised that if I really wanted to make
the most of online material in my learning journey, I&amp;rsquo;d need to learn how to read
music. Thankfully, reading drum notation is rather straightforward compared to
other instruments (or so I think). Things were all well and good until I realised
one day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I make the time to practice and reach the drumming goals I&amp;rsquo;d set for myself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m quite a goal oriented person and so naturally I had set ambitious goals for
myself. These goals were different from the ones I&amp;rsquo;d been setting for most of
my life, which would often be related to studies or work. These were goals where
I didn&amp;rsquo;t care as much if I went off track. They were more like a north star and
had the ability to steer me back on course if I went too far astray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lo and behold, I saw that the best way for me to make the time to practice was
to start waking up at 5 am in the morning. Yes. 5 am. I had tried practice
at more reasonable times but it just wasn&amp;rsquo;t consistent. I had never thought
there&amp;rsquo;d by anything that would make me jump out of bed this way. And now I&amp;rsquo;d
found it. And I was jumping out of bed. During COVID. The drums helped me stay
sane - though likely at the expense of my understanding wife&amp;rsquo;s sanity 🤣.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was experimenting with different material, playing along to songs I loved and even started learning to play &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-handed_drumming&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;open handed&lt;/a&gt; where instead of crossing your hands so your right (for most people, dominant) hand is on the hihat keeping time and you use your left hand on the snare. By playing open handed, as a right handed drummer, I was using my left hand to keep time, which meant I was using it on average 4 times more than my right hand. This was incredibly awkward and frustrating in the beginning. However, I stuck to it and configured my kit to suit this style of playing too:&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-hi-hat-left-setup-incredibly-low-for-open-handed-playing&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Hi hat (left) setup incredibly low for open handed playing&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /personal-values-part-i/kit-setup_hu8b4f4db4d2a4b8d46a2052a4896f6c76_2077477_cedb6ddcfa6298de0ae9e97fd8cadd10.webp 400w,
               /personal-values-part-i/kit-setup_hu8b4f4db4d2a4b8d46a2052a4896f6c76_2077477_f010c97bdfe89e3ae187c88cffbac3b9.webp 760w,
               /personal-values-part-i/kit-setup_hu8b4f4db4d2a4b8d46a2052a4896f6c76_2077477_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-i/kit-setup_hu8b4f4db4d2a4b8d46a2052a4896f6c76_2077477_cedb6ddcfa6298de0ae9e97fd8cadd10.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;570&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Hi hat (left) setup incredibly low for open handed playing
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical practice session eventually came to be an hour or more of playing
between 2-3 exercises, on a 15-20 minute break. Sound boring? I found it to be
rather meditative actually. This setup was a result of a lot of self-reflection
on what makes a good practice session. Benny Greb&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/56515701-effective-practicing-for-musicians&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Effective practicing for musicians&lt;/a&gt; had a lot of wisdom to share on
the topic and much like Essentialism, the message was the same: Choosing is not
losing. You need to make choices to go deeper and further on your topic of
interest. This is especially true for something like drumming where there is
more than an analytical understanding that you need to undertake to execute a
particular pattern on the drums. You need to literally drill that pattern down
into your body to the point where your muscle memory can take over and execute
the pattern instinctively at will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming to this realisation wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy. While it&amp;rsquo;s great having all this
information on our finger tips with platforms like youtube and social media but
these platforms are also a constant reminder of the different way&amp;rsquo;s that
you&amp;rsquo;re not &lt;code&gt;enough&lt;/code&gt; where you are right now. We are constantly bombarded with
what we don&amp;rsquo;t know, what&amp;rsquo;s cool and hip right now and 10 ways for you to
{{ insert a hyped up skill here }}.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;choices-were-always-there-but-i-never-realised-the-implications-of-failing-to-choose&#34;&gt;Choices were always there, but I never realised the implications of failing to choose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learnings I had from drumming could be easily transferred to other areas of
my life. I saw a number of parallels in my journey as a machine learning
practitioner. Scrolling through LinkedIn, is just a reminder of all the
technology frameworks you are yet to learn. That may not be everyone&amp;rsquo;s
experience but I bet a number of us feel that way. Feeling that way is normal
unless we become hyper aware of what exactly are the topics that we are
super-knowledgable and passionate about. And those topics have to necessarily
form a finite set, rather than one that changes depending which side of the
bed you went to sleep. The fear of missing out (FOMO) is what often prevents`
us from commiting to this finite set of topics that we dig our heels into.
Choosing one thing, necessarily means letting go of something else and who
wants that? Can&amp;rsquo;t we just have it all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back to my 5 am adventures, I was getting some exceptional results in
my drumming with the discipline of putting in the time consistently every day.
That was, until greed started to set in&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m quite big on productivity. I have a productivity system including a
number of tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.evernote.com&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; for taking notes,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.trello.com&#34;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; for big picture planning,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.sunsama.com&#34;&gt;Sunsama&lt;/a&gt; for a daily planner,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.todoist.com&#34;&gt;Todoist&lt;/a&gt; for capturing ideas and doing some tactical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prioritization,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google calendar and calendly for scheduling appointments,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.remarkable.com&#34;&gt;Remarkable&lt;/a&gt; for hand written digital notes that I can
send myself later for further processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the uninitiated, this would seem like a rather long list, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been
refining this system slowly over time and it feels very natural to me. Applying
Tiago Forte&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://fortelabs.com/blog/para/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PARA&lt;/a&gt; method allows me to
pretty much make sure nothing escapes my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    The productivity tools above may imply, to those in the know, that I&amp;rsquo;m following
some sort of &lt;a href=&#34;https://gettingthingsdone.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt; system.
However, I just kind of came up with this system on my own, following different
people on youtube who were probably taking inspiration from David Allen&amp;rsquo;s work.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waking up at 5 meant that I had roughly 4 hours before I started work and
that&amp;rsquo;s A LOT of time to get things done. Soon enough, I started to do more than
just drumming when I woke up at 5. I made a system where I tried to make sure
I &amp;ldquo;hit each area&amp;rdquo; a given number of times. You can think of it like going to
the gym and having a push/pull/legs like of setup. I was rotating through
different areas in my life to make sure &amp;ldquo;everything was in balance&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result you ask? I was no longer jumping out of bed anymore. I would wake up,
and look at the list of things I had planned to do for the time before 9 am.
There was likely also the fatigue from the long drawn COVID lockdowns coming
in, but I had basically taken the magic out of my mornings by overengineering
that time I had to myself. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, a number of good things came
out of this time, such as for example a scraper of immoweb that I wrote
around this time (see blog entry &lt;a href=&#34;https://rohailtaimour.com/a-scraper-that-scales-part-i/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before I started to wake up, only to hit the snooze
button and go back to bed once I saw the long todo list I had left for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew that I needed to reorient myself and get back to the basics. I had let
my greed, to get more done, get the best of me. I knew at this time that I
needed a value system that would help me decide what&amp;rsquo;s worth (to me) spending
time on and what&amp;rsquo;s better left on the backlog (or better yet, not even added to
the backlog to begin with!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-was-just-the-beginning&#34;&gt;This was just the beginning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be easy coming up a list of values to give me a
foundation. Making such decisions is hard! For example, if you had to choose
between knowledge and imagination, which value would you prioritize? What if
you had to choose between Integrity and Accountability? Not easy is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I explore how these insights helped me formulate my values in a following
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-ii/&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;. Stay posted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Soon, playing on the electronic kit wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough and I needed to rent out
a practice room
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-yamaha-dtx-452&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Yamaha DTX 452&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /personal-values-part-i/real-kit_hucdbd301978b6aa20cba4b1cc8f601d32_2518857_a8bbe05be4b6e7b591bf08a7361b890e.webp 400w,
               /personal-values-part-i/real-kit_hucdbd301978b6aa20cba4b1cc8f601d32_2518857_ab5ee5a0177452aa020f7c1db4511690.webp 760w,
               /personal-values-part-i/real-kit_hucdbd301978b6aa20cba4b1cc8f601d32_2518857_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-i/real-kit_hucdbd301978b6aa20cba4b1cc8f601d32_2518857_a8bbe05be4b6e7b591bf08a7361b890e.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Yamaha DTX 452
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stateful Applications Need to Be Designed Differently</title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/a-scraper-that-scales-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 16:15:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/a-scraper-that-scales-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Complete me&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Motivation to Build a Scraper in Python</title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/a-scraper-that-scales-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 16:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/a-scraper-that-scales-part-i/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#implementing-the-proof-of-concept&#34;&gt;Implementing the Proof of concept&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#a-sidenote-on-bayesian-statistics&#34;&gt;A sidenote on Bayesian statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#revisiting-the-implementation-once-again&#34;&gt;Revisiting the implementation once again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#areas-of-improvement&#34;&gt;Areas of improvement&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#1-efficiency-in-data-scraping&#34;&gt;1. Efficiency in Data Scraping&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#2-dependency-management&#34;&gt;2. Dependency Management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#3-code-refactoring-for-readability-and-maintainability&#34;&gt;3. Code Refactoring for Readability and Maintainability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#5-data-storage-and-validation&#34;&gt;5. Data Storage and Validation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#final-comments&#34;&gt;Final comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that period when most parts of the world were in a lockdown due to
COVID? Yes, we&amp;rsquo;re nearing the end of 2023 and COVID seems like a distant memory
at this point. However, like I imagine many of us, I suddenly found that being
restricted in movement and social interaction to a large extent, I had a lot
more time at my disposal. This was also a time where my wife and I realised that
we could have more space for ourselves so each of us could have an office setup
we could be happy with. This also being a time of low interest rates to
encourage consumption in the economy, it was an especially interesting property
market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seemed as good a time as any to write a scraper for Belgium&amp;rsquo;s most popular
property listings website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://immoweb.be&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;immoweb&lt;/a&gt;. My desire for this
first version was to first, be able to have a very general idea of the Brussels
property market. Thereafter, I would launch this script every few days to look
at the new  properties. The output of this script would be a CSV that I&amp;rsquo;d use
to spot good deals and have all the relevant information I&amp;rsquo;d need to schedule
visits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;implementing-the-proof-of-concept&#34;&gt;Implementing the Proof of concept&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was running this script from a windows machine at the time and having done a
scraping project once before already, knew that I&amp;rsquo;d start with &lt;code&gt;selenium&lt;/code&gt; for
the browser automation and parsing of the html. The setup required that I choose
a browser and a corresponding geckodriver (with the appropriate version for your
browser) to go along with it. I&amp;rsquo;ve used firefox and edge browsers (and their
respective drivers) for different iterations of the  scraper implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After messing around with developer tools, looking into the dom&amp;rsquo;s containing
the information I was looking for using &lt;code&gt;inspect&lt;/code&gt;, I had a script that was doing
the job. I made a conda export of the environment I used for the scraping in
case I ever needed to revisit this work again. This script did the job and I
was quite happy leaving it at that with an environment export so I could pick
up from this analysis when needed. This version of the script can be found
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roumail/immoweb-scraper/tree/second_run&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for
those who are interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-sidenote-on-bayesian-statistics&#34;&gt;A sidenote on Bayesian statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the longest time I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of Bayesian statistics. Being able to
explicitly encode your modelling assumptions in the form of priors, as well as
being very deliberate in reconstructing the data generating process of the
phenomenon you&amp;rsquo;re modelling. You can visually verify how well your model is
generalizing by doing what is called a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Posterior_predictive_distribution&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;posterior predictive check&lt;/a&gt;. The computational aspects of MCMC sampling
also appeals to the nerd in me, while the convergence of your sampler gives
indications about how well-informed a hypothesis you have for your data
generating process. An ill-formulated model will simply not converge,
unlike a number of other approaches which would always give a solution and then
you&amp;rsquo;re left to figure out if you&amp;rsquo;re overfitting or underfitting. Then there is
the fact that you are always able to work with distributions of your phenomenon
of interest rather than relying solely on point estimates like we would in most
other methods. There&amp;rsquo;s a number of fascinating things that are possible with
these posterior distributions, which include bayesian decision making. I will
link to a great discussion on the subject by Thomas Wiecki on the subject
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twiecki.io/blog/2019/01/14/supply_chain/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; where we can see how
to use our models to directly show the impact of uncertainy on real business
metrics rather than arcane statistical metrics such as &lt;code&gt;mean squared error&lt;/code&gt;,
&lt;code&gt;f1 score&lt;/code&gt; and the like which don&amp;rsquo;t hold any real business meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I have my bias for these methods and using these models bring their
own challenges. In some cases, traditional machine learning approaches would
give better performance without sacrificing interpretability and help you reach
a conclusion faster than using these bespoke modelling approaches. Nonetheless,
I was on the lookout for an opportunity to find a dataset where I could exploit
the natural hierarchical structure of data in a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bayesian_hierarchical_modeling&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;hierarchical modelling&lt;/a&gt;
or the flexiblity of Gaussian process modelling to capture the intricaties of
non-linear processes. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pymc.io/projects/examples/en/latest/gaussian_processes/GP-smoothing.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; shows the distinction between modelling
the same problem as a regression vs using a gaussian process smoothing model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;revisiting-the-implementation-once-again&#34;&gt;Revisiting the implementation once again&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any data scientist or machine learning practitioner will tell you about their
struggles with data. It&amp;rsquo;s either data quality (or lack thereof) or just the lack
of data itself for performing interesting analyses. Then it suddenly occurred
to me: property data is perfect for the experiments I wanted to conduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scraping property prices over time gives the opportunity to model property
prices over time and ask interesting questions, including, but not limited to
the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are rental property prices growing at the same rate as purchase properties?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do we observe a similar growth rate across different communes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are properties in the same commune priced similarly and if so, how much does
this vary by commune?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the most important determinants of price?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dataset of this nature contains elements of time series analysis since
property prices evolve over time. There is also a natural structure in the data
that can be exploited since we can indeed expect properties within communes to
be similarly priced. This would be a place where we can use Gaussian process
modelling to capture the underlying trends and fluctuations in property
prices within each commune. We can use property proximity to model the inherent
spatial relationships between properties, assuming that properties closer to
each other are more likely to have similar prices!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By revisiting my initial scraper implementation with this newfound focus, I am
not just enhancing a tool; I am building a robust data collection pipeline
that will serve as the backbone for these sophisticated analytical experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;areas-of-improvement&#34;&gt;Areas of improvement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a clear goal in mind, I identified several key areas to refine the
scraper&amp;rsquo;s implementation. These improvements were aimed at making the scraper
more efficient, easier to manage, and more robust for data collection and
analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-efficiency-in-data-scraping&#34;&gt;1. Efficiency in Data Scraping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switch to Beautiful Soup: I wanted to transition from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/selenium/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Selenium&lt;/a&gt; to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/beautifulsoup4/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Beautiful Soup&lt;/a&gt; for parsing raw
HTML. This change ought to significantly reduced the time needed to scrape data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parametrization of Postal Codes: Allowing postal codes as an input parameter
to make the scraper more flexible. I was initially only looking into a few
communes in Brussels that I was interested in. However, if I wanted to do some
interesting analyses, I also wanted to consider communes neighboring Brussels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-dependency-management&#34;&gt;2. Dependency Management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use of Poetry: To manage the project&amp;rsquo;s dependencies more effectively, I
wanted to convert the script into a Python package and used &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Poetry&lt;/a&gt; for managing
the dependencies. This streamlines the installation process and allows me to
manage the package versions in a systematic version. This would be especially
useful as we dockerize the analysis in the future and build a CI/CD pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementation of Typer: I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/typer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Typer&lt;/a&gt; to
create a command-line interface from the main application entrypoint. I&amp;rsquo;ve
effectively transitioned to using this instead of
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/click/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-code-refactoring-for-readability-and-maintainability&#34;&gt;3. Code Refactoring for Readability and Maintainability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Object-Oriented Approach: I wanted to refactor the code to use Python classes
instead of just functions where appropriate. By using meaningful class names, the
code can become self-documenting and easier to maintain and extend in the long
run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-data-storage-and-validation&#34;&gt;5. Data Storage and Validation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SQLite Database: I wanted to use a SQLite database with an initial schema to
store the data I&amp;rsquo;d be accumulating over time. I&amp;rsquo;ve really enjoyed working with
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/SQLAlchemy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;SQLAlchemy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as the ORM mapper to interact with the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Validation with Pydantic: Before adding the scraped data to the database,
I implemented validation checks using
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/pydantic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pydantic&lt;/a&gt;. This ensured that only
high-quality, accurate data was stored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By focusing on these areas, I aimed to build a scraper that was not just a
one-off script but a robust data collection tool capable of supporting more
complex analyses and experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-comments&#34;&gt;Final comments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next blog &lt;a href=&#34;https://rohailtaimour.com/a-scraper-that-scales-part-ii/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; in the series, I will go over the implementation details.
For those interested, you can find the current state of the project
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roumail/immoweb-scraper/tree/v1.0.0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my Website! 👋</title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/post/20231017-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/post/20231017-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Exciting News: My Website is Live! 🎉&lt;br&gt;
Hello everyone, and welcome to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.rohailtaimour.com&lt;/a&gt;! I am incredibly excited to announce that my website is officially live. 🚀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built it Myself with Hugo 🛠️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the tech world, there are countless ways to build a website, many of which offer quick and easy solutions. However, I chose to take a different route by building this website myself using Hugo. The journey was challenging but immensely rewarding, providing me with hands-on experience that goes beyond just writing code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosted on GitHub Pages with GitHub Actions 🌐&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most enlightening aspects of this project was learning how to host a static website using GitHub Pages and automating the deployment process with GitHub Actions. Surprisingly, this was not as daunting as it sounds, and I found the experience to be relatively straightforward. Keep an eye out for a future blog post where I&amp;rsquo;ll document this process in detail!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customized to My Needs 🎨&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey didn’t stop at just building the website; I’ve also customized it to suit my preferences and needs. This involved tweaking the template to accommodate blog series, implementing a contact form, and even adding the ability for visitors to comment on blog posts. One challenge still ahead is optimizing the website for SEO—turns out my MySpace account is incredibly resilient in search rankings!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Coming Up 📝&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website will serve as my digital canvas. I’ll use it to share my insights and experiences on a range of topics: from Python development, machine learning, and data engineering, to open-source technology frameworks and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Feedback is Welcome 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to explore the website and let me know what you think. Your feedback is invaluable and will help me continue to improve this digital space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for visiting, and stay tuned for exciting content!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.rohailtaimour.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;--block-collection&#34;&gt;- block: collection&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;id-talks&#34;&gt;id: talks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;content&#34;&gt;content:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;title-recent--upcoming-talks&#34;&gt;title: Recent &amp;amp; Upcoming Talks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;filters&#34;&gt;filters:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;folders&#34;&gt;folders:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;--event&#34;&gt;- event&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;design:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;columns-2&#34;&gt;columns: &amp;lsquo;2&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;view-compact&#34;&gt;view: compact&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;---block-portfolio&#34;&gt;# - block: portfolio&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----id-projects&#34;&gt;#     id: projects&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----content&#34;&gt;#     content:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----title-projects&#34;&gt;#     title: Projects&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----filters&#34;&gt;#     filters:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;---------folders&#34;&gt;#         folders:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----------project&#34;&gt;#         - project&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;------default-filter-index-eg-0-corresponds-to-the-first-filter_button-instance-below&#34;&gt;#     # Default filter index (e.g. 0 corresponds to the first &lt;code&gt;filter_button&lt;/code&gt; instance below).&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----default_button_index-0&#34;&gt;#     default_button_index: 0&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;------filter-toolbar-optional&#34;&gt;#     # Filter toolbar (optional).&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;------add-or-remove-as-many-filters-filter_button-instances-as-you-like&#34;&gt;#     # Add or remove as many filters (&lt;code&gt;filter_button&lt;/code&gt; instances) as you like.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;------to-show-all-items-set-tag-to-&#34;&gt;#     # To show all items, set &lt;code&gt;tag&lt;/code&gt; to &amp;ldquo;*&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;------to-filter-by-a-specific-tag-set-tag-to-an-existing-tag-name&#34;&gt;#     # To filter by a specific tag, set &lt;code&gt;tag&lt;/code&gt; to an existing tag name.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;------to-remove-the-toolbar-delete-the-entire-filter_button-block&#34;&gt;#     # To remove the toolbar, delete the entire &lt;code&gt;filter_button&lt;/code&gt; block.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----buttons&#34;&gt;#     buttons:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----------name-all&#34;&gt;#         - name: All&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;---------tag-&#34;&gt;#         tag: &amp;lsquo;*&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----------name-deep-learning&#34;&gt;#         - name: Deep Learning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;---------tag-deep-learning&#34;&gt;#         tag: Deep Learning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----------name-other&#34;&gt;#         - name: Other&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;---------tag-demo&#34;&gt;#         tag: Demo&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----design&#34;&gt;#     design:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;------choose-how-many-columns-the-section-has-valid-values-1-or-2&#34;&gt;#     # Choose how many columns the section has. Valid values: &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;2&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----columns-1&#34;&gt;#     columns: &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----view-showcase&#34;&gt;#     view: showcase&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;------for-showcase-view-flip-alternate-rows&#34;&gt;#     # For Showcase view, flip alternate rows?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-----flip_alt_rows-false&#34;&gt;#     flip_alt_rows: false&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example preprint / working paper</title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/publication/preprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/publication/preprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the publication&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;full text&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;supplementary notes&lt;/strong&gt; here. You can use rich formatting such as including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/pdf-export/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Eating...&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Only the speaker can read these notes
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Press &lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;`S`&lt;/span&gt; key to view
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  {{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/media/boards.jpg&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;#0000FF&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;my-style&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;navy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example journal article</title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/publication/journal-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/publication/journal-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the publication&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;full text&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;supplementary notes&lt;/strong&gt; here. You can use rich formatting such as including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example conference paper</title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/publication/conference-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/publication/conference-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the publication&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;full text&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;supplementary notes&lt;/strong&gt; here. You can use rich formatting such as including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitemap</title>
      <link>https://rohailtaimour.com/sitemap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rohailtaimour.com/sitemap/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
