<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Musings from Rohail</title>
    <link>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falling Into Analysis Paralysis</title>
      <link>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/analysis-paralysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:49:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/analysis-paralysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;dig-deeper-if-youre-hesitating&#34;&gt;Dig deeper if you&amp;rsquo;re hesitating&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I wrote my last entry! It&amp;rsquo;s been a busy period with the
adaptations needed in one&amp;rsquo;s life after they become new parents. It&amp;rsquo;s been
challenging to say the least. However, writing new entries doesn&amp;rsquo;t take as much
time once you&amp;rsquo;ve put your mind to it. Which brings up the first question I&amp;rsquo;ve
been pondering ever since I decided to write a blog: Is this platform a digital
garden for me to test out new ideas or more a place for me to unleash and make
sense of my inner world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog entry is clearly one of the latter. And this is not a journal entry
either, which would be rather more personal in nature. These entries stay on the
web for the foreseeable future (unless I take them down myself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the answer to the main thesis of this blog entry is ofcourse also: all of
the above. This was one of the primary reasons I have categories for each of the
main topics I&amp;rsquo;m planning to be writing on. So deciding to write on one topic
does not at all preclude the other. That micro-decision, however, is where the
issue begins. It presents the perfect opportunity to ruminate over getting
certain details right that don&amp;rsquo;t really matter at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that I certainly fall victim to this now and again. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking
for sometime now to finish writing the series on the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com/content/post/series-building-a-scraper-that-scales/_index.md&#34;&gt;scraper&lt;/a&gt;. There
remain a number of ideas remaining to tackle in that series and there&amp;rsquo;s a few
lazy shortcuts I took I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking to rectify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then on the other hand, I have the third part of the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com/content/post/series-decoding-rohail/_index.md&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; on decoding myself. The
values that I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to base myself off, to guide me through life if you
will, leave a lot of room for interpretation. Circumstances over the past few
months, with the birth of our daughter, a change in job, the industry I&amp;rsquo;m
working on, and I&amp;rsquo;ve even started having regular jam sessions with a band as a
drummer. These are exciting times and have left me with a lot to reflect and
ponder over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This explains the stream of nature blog entry we have here because it&amp;rsquo;s a
reaffirmation of what this blog is ultimately about: mostly unfiltered
expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;its-about-showing-up-make-it-happen&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about showing up: make it happen!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my efforts so far have focused on setting up the website, learning the
different pieces of the puzzle when it comes to statically generated websites.
My goal was always to avoid spending too much time editing the content that I
put out. The tools we have today allow us to run into loops editing things to
our hearts desire. For example, I read somewhere that some of our favourite
bands, when they recorded albums, would only get one take to record the whole
thing due to technology constraints of the time. These kind of constraints mean
that firstly, you need to have mastered your material to the point where you can
do everything in one take and secondly, that some mistakes are bound to creep
in. I think there was probably a far more tolerant view of these mistakes at the
time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to my writing, I can be quite accepting of it&amp;rsquo;s imperfections.
That is, unless, I&amp;rsquo;m actually writing software. In the imperative paradigm of
programming, where you have to give the computer complete instructions of what
needs to be done, for the program to perform as expected, we need to provide
sufficient instructions. Hence, these instructions require a certain amount of
rigorousness, thinking of different edge cases: some of which you are only bound
to find at runtime or when the users of the software use it in unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hesitating to write because I have been inundated with a rush of new
information, whether it was from technologies I was encountering in my recent
role, or technical books I was reading at the moment. The book,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Designing-Data-Intensive-Applications-Reliable-Maintainable/dp/1449373321/ref=sr_1_1?crid=3FJXGHQ63JL2S&amp;amp;keywords=designing&amp;#43;data-intensive&amp;#43;applications&amp;#43;by&amp;#43;martin&amp;#43;kleppmann&amp;amp;qid=1697911731&amp;amp;sprefix=designing&amp;#43;data%2Caps%2C74&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Designing Data-Intensive Applications&lt;/a&gt;,
for example is a classic and has left me with a lot of food for thought. It&amp;rsquo;s
fundamentally changed the way I look at any application I work on in the past.
However, writing an article discussing it becomes more of a research endeavour,
demanding a somewhat rigorous attitude. And hence, the procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com/media/albums/technical-list-2023/data-intensive.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key takeaway here is that it&amp;rsquo;s more important to show up, to write blog
entries, whatever they may happen to be, than to curate the non-existent entries
you will have on your website. Clearly I had projected this website to be more
of a technical playground and was stuck to that idea instead of letting the
entries come and for the website to organically grow as it will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tendency to go for over complicated solutions, or planning for solutions to
problems that don&amp;rsquo;t exist yet is far too common. I see it all the time amongst
developers, and I catch myself doing this far too often. I recently spotted this
in a drumming context, where I saw how different playing in a band can be
compared to practicing on your own. Since the past few months that I&amp;rsquo;ve been
playing drums with a guitarist and bassist, it&amp;rsquo;s increased my sense of musical
awareness and forced me revisit some basics I had started to gloss over.
Concretely speaking, I had been drumming at a bpm of about 70-80 for most of the
past three years I had been practicing. Suddenly, I needed to play at almost
double that bpm because that&amp;rsquo;s how fast most rock is played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;best-to-accept-vulnerability-when-youre-aiming-to-show-up&#34;&gt;Best to accept vulnerability when you&amp;rsquo;re aiming to show up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read the book, Who moved my cheese, in the beginning of last year at what may
have been the best possible time to read it. I had started on my freelance
journey about six months ago and I had to start looking for my next mission soon
after returning from holidays. In many ways, once you become a freelancer, you
have to come to terms with accepting uncertainty. I had been a permanent
employee at the same company for all of my professional working experience and
it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to become detached from the realities of looking for new
opportunities. This book punches way above it&amp;rsquo;s weight, for the amount of wisdom
it imparts in a very short number of pages. The key takeaway? How to keep a
healthy mindset about change and reframing it such that you see change for what
it really is: a chance for you to encounter something, perhaps much better than
what you could have possibly imagined for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /analysis-paralysis/cheese_hue9af93e9b876f3658344384ff139110c_70161_c5f9bc9349e8d888fad47fa26da4ba98.webp 400w,
               /analysis-paralysis/cheese_hue9af93e9b876f3658344384ff139110c_70161_9175055eaa9f588e6fa951278089ad52.webp 760w,
               /analysis-paralysis/cheese_hue9af93e9b876f3658344384ff139110c_70161_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com/analysis-paralysis/cheese_hue9af93e9b876f3658344384ff139110c_70161_c5f9bc9349e8d888fad47fa26da4ba98.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;502&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is we all think we know exactly how things will play out and most
often than not, it&amp;rsquo;s the fear of change and uncertainty that&amp;rsquo;s stopping you from
taking that next step. That&amp;rsquo;s where vulnerability comes in, where you take a
step, not knowing all the details. This was around the time that I was doing a
lot of reflection on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-ii/#my-values&#34;&gt;values&lt;/a&gt; and I had
realised that my list of values had one half that I perceived myself to be
naturally good at while there was another half which I tended to ignore. Turns
out the values I was ignoring were the ones that were key to handling
uncertainty better and that allowed me to remain exposed in vulnerable
situations without pulling my hair out as I might have done not too long ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-ingredients-to-staying-strong-when-feeling-exposed&#34;&gt;Key ingredients to staying strong when feeling exposed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What purpose do vague words like the ones below serve us anyway when we&amp;rsquo;re faced
with a challenging situation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acceptance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplicity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that it&amp;rsquo;s good that these words are ambiguous. At
different points in your life, they can mean different things to you.
Nonetheless, I find that the key to withstand vulnerability is to remember that
not ever situation calls for a complex solution. We need to be embrace
&lt;em&gt;Simplicity&lt;/em&gt; in our actions, have &lt;em&gt;Faith&lt;/em&gt; that we&amp;rsquo;re on the right track. We need
to &lt;em&gt;Accept&lt;/em&gt; that not everything pan out as we&amp;rsquo;d want and remember to stay
&lt;em&gt;Humble&lt;/em&gt; since it&amp;rsquo;s very likely we were at least partially wrong about any
meaningful endeavour we take. Do we need to fear making mistakes? Why should we?
Fear makes life interesting because it means you&amp;rsquo;re pushing yourself out of your
comfort zone. I guess we can ask ourselves, if we&amp;rsquo;d really like a life without
fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;circling-back-to-this-blog&#34;&gt;Circling back to this blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what this blog will be about. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to put any labels to
what it be a few years from now. I don&amp;rsquo;t even have to care what it will look
like a few entries from now. It&amp;rsquo;s more important to show up, write and let it
take on a life of it&amp;rsquo;s own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank&amp;rsquo;s for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Joined a Band as a Drummer!</title>
      <link>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 16:50:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;milestone-unlocked-my-first-band&#34;&gt;Milestone unlocked: My first band&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m part of a few facebook groups where people post about looking for jam
partners or asking for information about where there&amp;rsquo;d be live music playing in
Brussels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a similar post in one of these groups asking for information about a
place I can book a practice room that contains a drum kit. As you would have it,
by a matter of pure luck, I got in touch with someone looking for a drummer. It
seems he happened to see one of my post looking for a rehearsal room and decided
to get in touch for a few projects he was part of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;d already been a while I&amp;rsquo;d been looking to play along with folks to get to
that next level as a musician. Practicing and improving your techniques is
something I really enjoy but at the end of the day, we play our preferred
instruments to make Music. This was something my drum teacher always told me,
that all technique and tools at our disposal ultimately are only meant to serve
the Music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, there are certain aspects of playing music, which only come from
playing with each other. There is an element of communication, improvisation and
when these elements come together in a natural manner, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing that&amp;rsquo;s
more satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-new-reason-to-practice-a-different-focus-altogether&#34;&gt;A new reason to practice, a different focus altogether!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would be the first to admit that I can get quite geeky about percussive
instruments in general. For about 8 months I picked up the tabla, a percussive
instrument prevalent in the musical tradition from the subcontinent. There&amp;rsquo;s a
few obvious reasons to be fascinated by the tabla. I grew up listening to the
instrument and had a natural connection with the rhythmic tradition. Secondly,
this is a percussive instrument that can be tuned in different pitches, making
it sound like a melodic instrument in the hands of the right person. Go check
out this
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HKX0XoO0jaI&amp;amp;ab_channel=RetrointheMetro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;
by the Maestro Zakir Hussain if you want to see that in action. However, what&amp;rsquo;s
really the most amazing part of the tabla is that the tradition requires one to
master the rhythm vocally before attempting to play it on the instrument.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/tabla_hu320711c7e4d0a631a33416d45fc39afd_1692072_bc99d3f7482b1cbdfecce9d0127d51ae.webp 400w,
               /post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/tabla_hu320711c7e4d0a631a33416d45fc39afd_1692072_e836a1104e31a55a95ce81f20ce5e696.webp 760w,
               /post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/tabla_hu320711c7e4d0a631a33416d45fc39afd_1692072_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/tabla_hu320711c7e4d0a631a33416d45fc39afd_1692072_bc99d3f7482b1cbdfecce9d0127d51ae.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;530&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HKX0XoO0jaI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each sound that tabla can make (and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of them), has been assigned a
vocal counterpart. This is a very rich concept can be adapted and applied to the
drumset setting and leads to some very creative practice ideas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explore-vs-exploit-when-to-know-you-need-to-keep-digging-in-deeper&#34;&gt;Explore vs Exploit: When to know you need to keep digging in deeper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s been such a fantastic journey to learn about the Tabla, I eventually
had to put it on pause because I saw I was spreading myself too thin. As a
weekend warrior of sorts, when it comes to playing my instrument, you can&amp;rsquo;t let
your limited number of practice hours be dispersed across different activities.
You can, ofcourse, but there is a very hard tradeoff to be made here when you&amp;rsquo;re
counting on seeing progress in your playing, as a way to stay motivated in your
practice sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making that decision wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy. I have the impression human beings hesitate
before committing to something. We want to keep our options open. Why? Maybe
because it&amp;rsquo;s easier to make mistakes as a beginner but more difficult to show up
when you realize how much incremental effort&amp;rsquo;s really needed to realise
something. Taking the tabla as an example, I would have had to train my fingers
to be able to articulate the notes properly. This is an exercise that develops
slowly, as you develop the muscle memory over sustained and focused practice. I
saw this from my own experience when I started playing the drums using the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-handed_drumming&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Open handed&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; style. In a
nutshell, this style implies that a right handed player would need to develop
their left, weaker, hand to lead on the instrument. It took me months and even a
couple of years before I started to notice my left hand feeling on par, or at
least in the same category, as my dominant right hand. There&amp;rsquo;s a number of
advantages to being able to play this way and having gone through the steep
learning curve, I can now take advantage of a higher degree of ambidexterity on
the drum kit. Had I been unable to commit to this approach at the start of my
drumming journey, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been able to meet this drumming milestone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, while it is imperative spending time in the Exploit phase, honing in on
skills slowly and steadily over time, you cannot ignore the Explore phase.
Indeed, trying the tabla or even Open handed drumming when I first started was
the result of the Explore phase. It was something that I decided to move into
the Exploit phase once I decided committing to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;explore-periods-can-have-a-wider-spectrum-range-than-you-might-think&#34;&gt;Explore periods can have a wider spectrum range than you might think&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point, I thought that this stage is about looking into big ideas. As seen
in the figure below, that an Explore phase, necessarily entails a high amount of
uncertainty. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to see this phase a bit differently more recently.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/_hu588ab622fa13a15d46efaed8c58ad4dc_56319_38baf2fd4b5d5a2cb6a3fdead7db853b.webp 400w,
               /post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/_hu588ab622fa13a15d46efaed8c58ad4dc_56319_ee5ce1bba922e3f72d2cac6d3b8ff070.webp 760w,
               /post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/_hu588ab622fa13a15d46efaed8c58ad4dc_56319_edc5b49e4f99bd69acb72c17d47f3cfe.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/_hu588ab622fa13a15d46efaed8c58ad4dc_56319_38baf2fd4b5d5a2cb6a3fdead7db853b.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;431&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that we are constantly walking on the blurry line between Explore and
Exploit. In digging deeper, in the Exploit phase, you start to notice more and
more details, nuances, that were simply impossible for you to perceive earlier.
This is a fascinating observation I&amp;rsquo;ve made in many areas of my life and not
just drumming. In some ways, it&amp;rsquo;s about being open to coming across new paths
along the way you didn&amp;rsquo;t know existed before you start on your way. This is most
self-evident to me when I have a 20 minute session of playing a particular
groove. While playing this obviously monotonous pattern, my consciousness is
constantly evolving. Where ten minutes ago, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t move my limbs in harmony,
and I&amp;rsquo;d constantly be trying to lock in, say my right hand and left foot, the
coordination, suddenly, those limbs start to move subconsciously. I&amp;rsquo;m not even
thinking of it anymore, which leaves me the mental space to consider other
aspects of the groove: Am I playing at the right volume, what&amp;rsquo;s my right foot
doing and how does it &amp;ldquo;feel&amp;rdquo; striking the bass drum, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always try to enter this space during a practice session. This is where, as
drummers would say, you go from thinking the groove, to feeling it in your body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-can-always-choose-to-come-back-to-something---it-wont-go-anywhere&#34;&gt;You can always choose to come back to something - it won&amp;rsquo;t go anywhere&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started drumming, I went into a phase of buying all the classic
books I saw. I wanted one on Progressive drumming essentials, one on basic rock
grooves, one on coordination, etc. There was so much I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that it was
difficult knowing where to start and I had the tendency to rush moving onto new
material before really capturing the essence of the material. This anxiousness,
I now realise, was mostly because I was more concerned about where I needed to
be by a given point in time. I thought I could plan up front a year, or more,
into the future. However, it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t work that way. All drummers know the
book Stick Control, by George W. Lawrence Stone.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/1200x630bf-4124031017_hu082ec7775596841f28aef6fb968a2982_89180_7675993219af301fb58a5681705d1d35.webp 400w,
               /post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/1200x630bf-4124031017_hu082ec7775596841f28aef6fb968a2982_89180_06adbd3474527785af5757c3f1c4461f.webp 760w,
               /post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/1200x630bf-4124031017_hu082ec7775596841f28aef6fb968a2982_89180_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/1200x630bf-4124031017_hu082ec7775596841f28aef6fb968a2982_89180_7675993219af301fb58a5681705d1d35.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;399&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book has forty pages or so. But this isn&amp;rsquo;t a book you can &amp;ldquo;finish&amp;rdquo;. Each
page of this book are sticking patterns, indicating a rhythm to play and the
hand that needs to play it. Almost 4 years into drumming and I keep revisting
this book with a fresh pair of eyes. It&amp;rsquo;s a timeless book and a source of
endless material. At this point today, I can honestly say I haven&amp;rsquo;t made it past
the first four pages and I still think I got so much out of it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, previously, I&amp;rsquo;d always want to move on to the next book, and then the
one after that. Ofcourse, this was before I learnt that the Explore phase
doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be about taking on a new book to practice material, but really
imbibing the material in as many different ways as you possibly can. That&amp;rsquo;s the
best way I&amp;rsquo;ve found to make the material stick - so that you can improvise and
the material you&amp;rsquo;re practicing actually shows up in your playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of time for me to revisit those other books I have planned for.
That&amp;rsquo;s where faith comes in. I know I&amp;rsquo;d pick them up when the right time comes
in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my Website! 👋</title>
      <link>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/20231017-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/20231017-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Exciting News: My Website is Live! 🎉&lt;br&gt;
Hello everyone, and welcome to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.rohailtaimour.com&lt;/a&gt;! I am incredibly excited to
announce that my website is officially live. 🚀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built it Myself with Hugo 🛠️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the tech world, there are countless ways to build a website, many of which
offer quick and easy solutions. However, I chose to take a different route by
building this website myself using Hugo. The journey was challenging but
immensely rewarding, providing me with hands-on experience that goes beyond just
writing code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosted on GitHub Pages with GitHub Actions 🌐&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most enlightening aspects of this project was learning how to host a
static website using GitHub Pages and automating the deployment process with
GitHub Actions. Surprisingly, this was not as daunting as it sounds, and I found
the experience to be relatively straightforward. Keep an eye out for a future
blog post where I&amp;rsquo;ll document this process in detail!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customized to My Needs 🎨&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey didn’t stop at just building the website; I’ve also customized it to
suit my preferences and needs. This involved tweaking the template to
accommodate blog series, implementing a contact form, and even adding the
ability for visitors to comment on blog posts. One challenge still ahead is
optimizing the website for SEO—turns out my MySpace account is incredibly
resilient in search rankings!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Coming Up 📝&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website will serve as my digital canvas. I’ll use it to share my insights
and experiences on a range of topics: from Python development, machine learning,
and data engineering, to open-source technology frameworks and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Feedback is Welcome 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to explore the website and let me know what you think. Your feedback
is invaluable and will help me continue to improve this digital space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for visiting, and stay tuned for exciting content!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.rohailtaimour.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
