<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Musings from Rohail</title>
    <link>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 16:50:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Joined a Band as a Drummer!</title>
      <link>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 16:50:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/2023-11-02-i-joined-a-band-as-a-drummer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;milestone-unlocked-my-first-band&#34;&gt;Milestone unlocked: My first band&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m part of a number of different facebook groups where people post about
looking for jam partners or asking for information about where there&amp;rsquo;d be live
music playing in Brussels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a similar post in one of these groups asking for information about a
place I can book a practice room that contains a drum kit. As you would have it,
by a matter of pure luck, I got in touch with Nicholas, who was looking for a
drummer. It seems he happened to see one of my post looking for a rehearsal room
and decided to get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking to play along with folks to get to that next
level as a musician. Practicing and improving your techniques is something I
really enjoy but at the end of the day, we play our preferred instruments to
make music. This was always something my drum teacher taught me that in the end,
the techniques and tools we have are always there to serve music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, there are certain aspects of playing music, which only come from
playing with each other. There is an element of communication, improvisation and
when these elements come together in a natural manner, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing that&amp;rsquo;s
more satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a video of the second single from the second time we&amp;rsquo;ve jammed together
as a group!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/1128615181441179/permalink/1132430547726309/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Weird Times&lt;/a&gt;
on facebook!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Band members:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arnaud Veraart (Guitar/vocals)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rohail Taimour (Drum)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicolas Forthomme (Bass)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my Website! 👋</title>
      <link>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/20231017-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/post/20231017-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Exciting News: My Website is Live! 🎉&lt;br&gt;
Hello everyone, and welcome to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.rohailtaimour.com&lt;/a&gt;! I am incredibly excited to
announce that my website is officially live. 🚀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built it Myself with Hugo 🛠️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the tech world, there are countless ways to build a website, many of which
offer quick and easy solutions. However, I chose to take a different route by
building this website myself using Hugo. The journey was challenging but
immensely rewarding, providing me with hands-on experience that goes beyond just
writing code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosted on GitHub Pages with GitHub Actions 🌐&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most enlightening aspects of this project was learning how to host a
static website using GitHub Pages and automating the deployment process with
GitHub Actions. Surprisingly, this was not as daunting as it sounds, and I found
the experience to be relatively straightforward. Keep an eye out for a future
blog post where I&amp;rsquo;ll document this process in detail!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customized to My Needs 🎨&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey didn’t stop at just building the website; I’ve also customized it to
suit my preferences and needs. This involved tweaking the template to
accommodate blog series, implementing a contact form, and even adding the
ability for visitors to comment on blog posts. One challenge still ahead is
optimizing the website for SEO—turns out my MySpace account is incredibly
resilient in search rankings!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Coming Up 📝&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website will serve as my digital canvas. I’ll use it to share my insights
and experiences on a range of topics: from Python development, machine learning,
and data engineering, to open-source technology frameworks and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Feedback is Welcome 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to explore the website and let me know what you think. Your feedback
is invaluable and will help me continue to improve this digital space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for visiting, and stay tuned for exciting content!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.rohailtaimour.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
