<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>core values | Musings from Rohail</title>
    <link>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/tag/core-values/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.rohailtaimour.com/tag/core-values/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>core values</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 13:26:24 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>core values</title>
      <link>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/tag/core-values/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part III: Bringing your values into your daily life</title>
      <link>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 13:26:24 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-iii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-article-harder-to-write-than-expected&#34;&gt;An article harder to write than expected&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first created this website, my primary goal was to create series
articles: Write mostly technical content that needed exploring over a series of
posts. This desire sprung from the large number of posts I had read online,
which would introduce a topic at an introductory level and leave it at that.
Oftentimes, I wanted something that went a bit deeper and far too often, google
searches would amount to nothing in the end. Every once in a while, however,
I&amp;rsquo;ve come across authors who took a more series oriented approach. I&amp;rsquo;ve
benefitted immensely from such series, for example, while making this website.
Hugo, the engine i&amp;rsquo;m using to render this website from markdown content, didn&amp;rsquo;t
ship with a very natural way to create series blog posts and I had to put
something together for myself. Adding this functionality delayed my launch (
publishing my fist article) far longer than I care to admit (ahem, 6 months).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why say this all anyway? Have we gone off topic when this article was about how
to embed your prioritized values in your life? Well, yes and no. The short
answer is, I wish there was this one golden tip, or even a few, that I could
share with you, which would magically allow you to get clarity around your
values and find ways to embed them in your day to day life. I certainly wish it
was possible to be described within a thousand word article. I delayed &amp;amp;
hesitated writing this article, hoping for an epiphany in the meantime, that I&amp;rsquo;d
be able to share with you. This last point prevented me from writing more &amp;amp;
eventually I broke through it with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com/analysis-paralysis&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; here I
revisited my motivations for even putting this blog together. I hope what I&amp;rsquo;ve
come to learn is still worth sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;values-are-only-words-you-breathe-life-into&#34;&gt;Values are only words you breathe life into&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first few years of COVID had been a time of real introspection for me. I&amp;rsquo;ve
come that once you&amp;rsquo;ve decided on a few values to live by, embedding them in your
daily life still has some pre-requisites. It&amp;rsquo;s a process, which will be personal
to you &amp;amp; which would evolve much as you evolve as a person. Wait a minute
though-if we&amp;rsquo;re evolving as a person, then are our values also something that
need to be revisited? If our reference, the values &amp;amp; our process to embed them,
are both changing, then how do we make any sense of it all? In my experience,
you do not need to revisit your values every fully moon cycle. You can, if you
want. However, if you earnestly went through the process of defining them the
first time, I&amp;rsquo;d leave it at that. This is because values in themselves have no
meaning. They are only words. It&amp;rsquo;s your actions, what they mean to you and how
you decide to live them that brings those words to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a given point in time, you shortlisted &amp;ldquo;values&amp;rdquo; from a list of 100. You made
tradeoffs and assessed how you saw yourself. For example, loyalty, strength &amp;amp;
patience. If you had to choose one of these, and I presume everyone would choose
differently, can the choice of these words really change who we are? Does
choosing strength mean loyalty becomes any less important? That I think patience
is only for idiots? Of course not. What&amp;rsquo;s important here is to take note of the
mental process which led you to choose one value over another. Making that
choice is critical to reduce the noise and to have a sense of direction. The
tool we&amp;rsquo;ve just achieved will help guide us when we&amp;rsquo;re in need of direction.
When there&amp;rsquo;s a moment you&amp;rsquo;re faced with a tough decision and you&amp;rsquo;re able to
water down that conundrum in terms of values that you feel are conflicting with
each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;values-are-like-post-it-notes&#34;&gt;Values are like post-it notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember writing reminders on the palm of your hand for something you&amp;rsquo;re likely
to forget? Maybe you didn&amp;rsquo;t need to do that like I used to as a kid, but the
point is these values are little post-it notes for you to use for course
correction. Anytime you hesitate &amp;amp; feel lost you can revisit the choice you made
to be a certain version of yourself you had envisioned at a time of clarity.
Another reason why it&amp;rsquo;s not so important to get too attached to the value itself
is that your interpretation of the value will keep changing as you move through
life. Strength may mean something completely different to a youth in the prime
of their life and an elder with decades of wisdom behind them. Your attachment
to the word keeps deepening as you keep revisiting it, letting the words sink
deeper &amp;amp; deeper into the palms of your hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-importance-of-having-space-in-your-life&#34;&gt;The importance of having space in your life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a crucial ingredient in making any of this work. You can choose your
values, commit to them, but without having &amp;ldquo;space&amp;rdquo; in your life, you won&amp;rsquo;t get
too far. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about mental space where you can look inside yourself; be
willing to make some decisions about who you aspire to be. It is critical that
you understand and appreciate that these are choices YOU are making about
yourself and that these choices are more important than many other choices we
make in our day to day life. These are choices where we cannot let anyone else&amp;rsquo;s
opinions colour our own. This is your inner world. This will be the lens you use
to view the world around you. Therefore, we must learn to create space in our
life on an ongoing basis where we can come to get to know ourselves, be gracious
for who are, compassionate for who we are still unable to be and understand that
much like how the outside world can impact our inner being, our inner state can
have a massive impact on our outside world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;decision-fatigue-and-the-misconception-with-space&#34;&gt;Decision fatigue and the misconception with space&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A possible misconception about &amp;ldquo;space&amp;rdquo;, as we use this term, is it&amp;rsquo;s magnitude.
Do you need days of space? Hours? I often find myself falling for this trap, and
it&amp;rsquo;s the prime way to let procrastination get in the way of your goals. I don&amp;rsquo;t
know if this is an actual japanese rule, but it&amp;rsquo;s how I came across it: 5 minute
rule. The gist of this rule is to plan spending no more than 5 minutes when you
initially plan on getting a new habit. Have the discipline to stop when 5
minutes are over. Continue with this process for a fixed duration of time, until
you&amp;rsquo;re ready to bump it up to say 10 minutes, and then later at some point,
maybe fifteen minutes and so on. What this technique helps you avoid, is the
mental laziness of avoiding something when you&amp;rsquo;re feeling decision fatigued.
Don&amp;rsquo;t know what that is? It&amp;rsquo;s the feeling you have when you come back from a
long day and you have to decide what you want to eat. To make matters worse,
there&amp;rsquo;s no groceries in the fridge either. That is decision fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, we tend to stay more consistent when we have a pre-determined,
predictable time allotted for a new habit. Giving a 100 percent inconsistently,
does not yield better results than taking out small amounts of space,
consistently, to think about your values and how to embed them in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;much-remains-to-be-said&#34;&gt;Much remains to be said&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a few other mindset shifts, or perspectives that remain to be shared on
living your values. However, to keep this post from being longer still, I will
keep that for another article. This article will be picking up on the importance
of &lt;code&gt;surrender&lt;/code&gt; and how by changing the way I understood this word, had a
profound impact on the way I saw living my values. We will explore what it means
to live effortlessly and how living effortlessly, doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily translate
into living complacently.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part II: Unearthing Your True North</title>
      <link>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 18:24:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;values-exercise&#34;&gt;Values exercise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my last article on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-i/&#34;&gt;subject&lt;/a&gt;, I stressed the
importance of having a set of values to inspire you to make the tough decisions.
The toughest decisions for me often involved saying no. No to something cool I
wanted to do, without first finishing something else I had started. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to
change your mind about what&amp;rsquo;s important to you, as long as that&amp;rsquo;s not erratic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received a lot of help in getting this clarify from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://krisverle.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kris&lt;/a&gt;, who supported me in identifying and shortlisting
the top most values I held dear. Naturally, this was an iterative process and I
believe this is an exercise one can revisit multiple times since your values may
slowly shift over time. Heading into this exercise, I had the following goals,
in no particular order and non-exhaustive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be super clear on the different roles I &amp;ldquo;identify&amp;rdquo; with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find ways of making &amp;ldquo;sustainable&amp;rdquo; progress on each of the identified roles
above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut out procrastination from my life so I can move forward with my identified
priorities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refine my productivity systems to get the most out of them without
overwhelming myself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having tools and systems I can fall back on to handle moments of anxiety and
uncertainty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand better what makes me tick and refine how I &amp;ldquo;channel&amp;rdquo; my attention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning to appreciate the moment as it is instead of trying to control it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find ways of channeling my creativity in ways that are healthy and don&amp;rsquo;t
consume me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revisit some of the fundamental beliefs I held about myself and the world
around me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As can be seen, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t a short list of goals and I headed into my sessions
with Kris with an open mind and heart. My one and only true goal was to come out
of these sessions in a place where I was content with where I was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-attention-as-a-spider-web&#34;&gt;Your attention as a spider web&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone&amp;rsquo;s likely had that moment when you are suddenly able to separate you,
the one who notices, from the voice in your head. Oftentimes, it is a momentary
experience and soon enough you&amp;rsquo;re back to being completely identified with that
voice. That voice in your head, if allowed, can completely take over how you
perceive reality. Through the process of self-reflection and writing a journal
during certain crucial moments, I noticed how fickle your though process can be.
Trying reading what you wrote ten days ago and how far removed you may feel from
your own thoughts that felt all-encompassing the moment you were experiencing
them. This was a revelation to me and to anyone interested in hearing someone
describe these concepts can look upon
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.be/-/en/Julia-Cameron/dp/1788164296/ref=asc_df_1788164296/?tag=begogshpadde-21&amp;amp;linkCode=df0&amp;amp;hvadid=633392667541&amp;amp;hvpos=&amp;amp;hvnetw=g&amp;amp;hvrand=16438304293944555379&amp;amp;hvpone=&amp;amp;hvptwo=&amp;amp;hvqmt=&amp;amp;hvdev=c&amp;amp;hvdvcmdl=&amp;amp;hvlocint=&amp;amp;hvlocphy=1001006&amp;amp;hvtargid=pla-920673948416&amp;amp;psc=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Artist&amp;rsquo;s Way&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Untethered-Soul-Journey-Beyond-Yourself-ebook/dp/B003TU29WA/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1BBH1F4AW95S6&amp;amp;keywords=Untethered&amp;#43;Soul&amp;amp;qid=1698135346&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;sprefix=untethered&amp;#43;soul%2Cdigital-text%2C134&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Untethered Soul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in &lt;code&gt;The Untethered Soul&lt;/code&gt;, the voice in your head is like the
annoying room mate that you can&amp;rsquo;t get rid of and you have to learn to live with.
This voice has a tendency to create a spider web where the fundamental beliefs
you hold about yourself would pull you in and trap you from being to see things
for how they &lt;code&gt;truly&lt;/code&gt; are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this revelation already did wonders in how I began to deal with certain
situations in my life, make sure to take the time to &lt;code&gt;respond&lt;/code&gt;, rather than
&lt;code&gt;reacting&lt;/code&gt;. Making sure that my actions were grounded in the values I cherished
rather than from a place of fear, insecurity, etc. Nevertheless, I will speak
about three ideas in particular which made a huge difference in my life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieving goals may need you to make sacrifices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The choosing is losing mindset. Better to keep my options &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The myth of the &amp;lsquo;perfect time&amp;rsquo; for tackling big challenges&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sacrifices-needed-to-achieve-your-goals&#34;&gt;Sacrifices needed to achieve your goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us desire better than what we have today - but what are you willing to
give up to achieve those goals? This one was an eye opener for me when I saw how
I could change my &amp;ldquo;victim&amp;rdquo; mindset, where I was expecting things to be a certain
way without really giving up something in return. I&amp;rsquo;m normally super vigilant
about viewing myself as a &amp;ldquo;victim&amp;rdquo; in a given situation. I think it&amp;rsquo;s very
natural for us to fall into that pattern since it&amp;rsquo;s very convenient to shift
responsibility to something external. This self-defense mechanism prevents us to
feeling &amp;ldquo;less than&amp;rdquo; since the reason we&amp;rsquo;re not where we want to be is not in our
control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everytime I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed this mindset, I&amp;rsquo;ve immediately resolved it by finding
ways that I can either influence the situation using levers that are under my
control and if the situation is truly outside my control altogether, to simply
find ways to come to terms with the situation. Find a way to accept the
situation as it is: stop fighting reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my previous post in the series, I talked about the time I started waking up
at 5 am in the morning to get consistent around my drumming. I started doing
this because I began noticing the voice in my head making excuses for me about
how &amp;ldquo;busy&amp;rdquo; I am and how poor old me isn&amp;rsquo;t able to progress on their goals
because there just isn&amp;rsquo;t enough time to prioritize drumming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prioritizing things means making sacrifices and at that point in time, I started
to question the number of hours I REALLY needed to be able to function well in a
day. I know the conventional wisdom goes something like 8 hours of sleep at
night but I thought I&amp;rsquo;d test that wisdom for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are often fed ideas along the lines of
&lt;code&gt;you can have it all without getting uncomfortable&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
However, I have found that the more apt saying would be that
&lt;code&gt;you can have whatever you&#39;re willing to pay the cost for&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;choosing-is-losing&#34;&gt;Choosing is losing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a big one for me. I&amp;rsquo;ve made a number of decisions in my earlier life
based on this mindset. When given the option for breadth vs depth, I&amp;rsquo;d tend to
go for the option where I&amp;rsquo;d still have the option of pivoting to something else
if I&amp;rsquo;d want. Now it&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable idea and I&amp;rsquo;m not at all saying that we need
to box ourselves in ahead of time without having space to adapt. No, not at all.
However, we must understand that there&amp;rsquo;s a spectrum here where you have to
strike a balance between the two extremes. I&amp;rsquo;ve found that more often than not,
this mindset has prevented me from fully committing to a course of action. I
found that this &amp;ldquo;rational&amp;rdquo; side of my brain was often coming from a place of
fear and a preference for maintaining the &amp;ldquo;status-quo&amp;rdquo; that I&amp;rsquo;d be comfortable
with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I saw that while we may convince ourself that we have perfect
knowledge about a given situation when we&amp;rsquo;re making a decision, it&amp;rsquo;s often the
opposite that&amp;rsquo;s true. When you may view making a choice as &amp;ldquo;closing certain
options&amp;rdquo;, often it may be the complete opposite that&amp;rsquo;s true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now relating these ideas back to my drumming journey, I saw that in the initial
few months when I first started out, I went into a rabbit hole of all the
different things I wanted to learn and there was so much content out there. We
live in a fascinating world where there&amp;rsquo;s so much information on our fingertips.
So much so, that we are simply not able to dive deeper into topics and give them
the time and attention that they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can easily draw a parallel here with the field of data science and machine
learning where there&amp;rsquo;s so many new tools and frameworks coming out consistently.
The market would give the impression that people are sponges who immediately
soak up the latest frameworks in an infinitesimal amount of time once these
tools are released. Of course, This is very far from reality. It&amp;rsquo;s very well
known for professionals, in most fields, not just data science, to feel the
imposter syndrome. You come across all the different tools that are on your
study list and the years of experience that companies require candidates to
possess. I think you see where I&amp;rsquo;m going with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such a setting, where it&amp;rsquo;s so easy to feel that you&amp;rsquo;re not enough, it can be
convenient to prefer aiming for a superficial understanding of the content at
best. In drumming, that approach just doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. You have an extremely
visible feedback loop where for a given technique, pattern or song that you&amp;rsquo;re
learning to play, you are either able to play it, or you&amp;rsquo;re not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, it&amp;rsquo;s very easy for our mind to jump between different topics but we can&amp;rsquo;t
fool our bodies as easily. Building the muscle memory necessary for flawless and
natural drumming requires you to spend so much time with something that you can
move that you&amp;rsquo;re able to execute without any thought whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of approach necessitates that you limit the amount of content you work
with and increase the amount of time you spend with a certain concept before
moving on to something else. Moving on too early would mean your body hasn&amp;rsquo;t had
enough time to absorb the idea enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mindset has been a revelation for me and I&amp;rsquo;ve been applying it to my
professional life as well. I make conscious decisions when making a choice,
being fully aware of the opportunity costs by making this choice. Furthermore, I
also recognize the opportunity cost of failing to choose: a lack of clarity on
your goals, an inability to make progress, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-myth-of-the-perfect-time&#34;&gt;The myth of the &amp;ldquo;perfect time&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never considered myself to be one to procrastinate so much. Ofcourse,
that&amp;rsquo;s not entirely true and while I may tend to avoid procrastination in
certain aspects of my life, in other&amp;rsquo;s I do it far too much. I read a great
article on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://waitbutwhy.com/2013/10/why-procrastinators-procrastinate.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;procrastination&lt;/a&gt;
that you may find interesting.&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /personal-values-part-ii/NP%20brain_huf584c28369a34fd8213508d55282912c_136872_932323097e601f29c72d81e04cf97d1d.webp 400w,
               /personal-values-part-ii/NP%20brain_huf584c28369a34fd8213508d55282912c_136872_3577a0df17a7ca46541c341f37d21238.webp 760w,
               /personal-values-part-ii/NP%20brain_huf584c28369a34fd8213508d55282912c_136872_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-ii/NP%20brain_huf584c28369a34fd8213508d55282912c_136872_932323097e601f29c72d81e04cf97d1d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;506&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /personal-values-part-ii/P%20brain_huaa6769202a2ff51cb8a42a9203e96e49_175078_29def570355ae74d9ba72d54a1115ba2.webp 400w,
               /personal-values-part-ii/P%20brain_huaa6769202a2ff51cb8a42a9203e96e49_175078_e308ae0fad8ad1e9bd11dab3cb80f9aa.webp 760w,
               /personal-values-part-ii/P%20brain_huaa6769202a2ff51cb8a42a9203e96e49_175078_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-ii/P%20brain_huaa6769202a2ff51cb8a42a9203e96e49_175078_29def570355ae74d9ba72d54a1115ba2.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;506&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest fallacy you ask me? The idea that a worthwhile endeavour needs to be
done at a time and place some point in the future, when things would somehow be
better and you would also be better prepared somehow for this challenge.
Whenever I&amp;rsquo;ve felt this way, I&amp;rsquo;ve traced the sentiment back somehow to the
victim mindset I spoke about earlier. The idea that one is going through an
especially difficult time right now and that postponing this idea until later is
probably a better idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, let&amp;rsquo;s not get carried away with hurtful labels for ourselves either.
There are times when we need to be compassionate with ourselves, when going
through a period of change and give our mind and body the time to process the
experience in question. Like everything, there&amp;rsquo;s a spectrum, a very personal
one, where there comes a time when you must decide to act on things that
continuously rise up within you. Continuing to delay something indefinitely,
might ultimately mean that something isn&amp;rsquo;t as much of a priority to you as you&amp;rsquo;d
like to think it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing to act on things that we procrastinate is an amazing way to fill up on
your &amp;ldquo;personal accountability bank&amp;rdquo; (PAB). This was an idea I first came across
reading Stephen Covey&amp;rsquo;s book
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/First-Things-Stephen-R-Covey/dp/0684802031&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;First Things First&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;
where he discusses this amazing idea of how you must show up when you demand
something from yourself. Everytime we fail to show up, we make a small
withdrawal from our bank account and likewise, showing up is like making a
deposit to our account. Having a strong balance in our PAB allows us to ride a
spiral where we are iteratively able to set the bar higher for ourselves.
Besides, showing up for yourself is a great way to feel good about yourself and
also be there for others around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a certain point, delaying things meaningful to you because you can&amp;rsquo;t see the
impact of your decision all the way to the end, or because things are a bit
chaotic at the moment, starts to add up to make big withdrawals from your PAB.
That&amp;rsquo;s just the way it happens so it&amp;rsquo;s best to avoid denying it. Just to change
things up a bit, I will give a non-drumming example this time. Around the first
half of last year I finally decided that I will become a freelancer. I was quite
happy with the time I spent as a data scientist at UCB and I was excited to put
myself out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the point where I made that decision and where things eventually worked
out towards my first freelance contract, there was a six month period full of
background work, recruiter calls and general soul searching. Embracing
freelancing is making a commitment to uncertainty in a way that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t
comfortable with and I constantly questioned the timing of my action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, at a certain point, a leap of faith is needed, with self-belief that
while things might get tough along the way, you would be able to handle them.
Having a strong PAB really helps at such a point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-values&#34;&gt;My values&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to beat around the bush too much further, the result of my soul searching in
the shape and form of a list of values that resonate with me is given below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acceptance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Belonging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creativity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curiosity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commitment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplicity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expressiveness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boldness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perseverance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the values above fall in one of two categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Values I cherish and desire to better embody in my life and,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Values I deem a strength of mine and that I naturally gravitate towards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming to this list was a milestone for me because I finally had a reference to
help me choose amongst a number of interesting options, the ones that are best
aligned to my list of prioritized values. It allowed me to declutter my
headspace and allowed me to make choices I could confidently stand behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, arriving at this list is just the beginning. The bigger question is how
we can make sure to embed these values in our day to day life. How can we make
sure these values are more than words to you, written somewhere and forgotten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be exploring these ideas in more detail in the final
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rohailtaimour.com/personal-values-part-iii/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; in the series&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
